A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
عقرب دقائق مسرِع، مُذنّب ساقط
Conan's logic is the tonic for hearts tired by modern society!
استنتاجات كونان هي دواء القلوب !المُثقلة بالمجتمع الحديث
Today's the Kaitou Kid special! Detective and thief square off!
!اليوم حلقة خاصة لكايتو كيد !مواجهة بين المتحرّي واللصّ
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
I'm high school student Kudo Shinichi.
أنا المتحرّي في المدرسة الثانويّة، كودو شينتشي
I went with Mori Ran, childhood friend and classmate,
ذهبتُ مع صديقة طفولتي وزميلتي ران
to an amusement park,
لحديقة الملاهي
where I witnessed a suspicious deal involving a man in black.
وشاهدتُ هناك رجلاً برداء أسود يعقد صفقة مشبوهة
I was so engrossed with watching that I didn't see his partner hiding!
بينما كنتُ منشغلاً بالمشاهدة، لم أنتبه !لرفيقه الذي تسلّل ورائي
I was knocked down and given a poison.
أفقدني وعيي، وجعلني أتجرّع سمّاً
When I woke up, my body had shrunk!
!وبعدما أفقت، وجدتُ جسدي متقلّصاً
If they learned Kudo Shinichi was alive,
إذا اكتشفوا أنّ كودو شينتشي لا يزال على قيد الحياة
people around me would be in danger!
سيتعرّض جميع من حولي للخطر
After following Prof. Agasa's advice to conceal my identity,
أخذت بنصيحة البروفسور آغاسا وأخفيتُ هويّتي
Ran asked me my name and I quickly said...
...وعندما سألتني ران عن اسمي، أجبت
... "Edogawa Conan!"
"!إيدوغاوا كونان"
Then, to uncover information about them,
بعدها، كي أحصل على معلومات عنهم
I moved in with Ran and her detective father.
انتقلت للعيش مع ران وأبيها الذي يعمل متحرّياً
Conan vs. Kaitou Kid
كونان ضدّ كايتو كيد
Kaitou #1412?
كايتو 1412؟
Yeah! He's an older thief that all the young girls are crazy about!
نعم! إنّه لصٌّ في منتصف العمر !يأسر قلوب كلّ الفتيات الآن
"Older"?
منتصف العمر؟
Your dad's a detective and you never heard of him?!
والدك متحرٍّ ولم تسمعي به؟
That doesn't mean I love following crimes.
لا يعني ذلك أنّي أحبّ متابعة الجرائم
But hear me out!
!اسمعيني
So you want my dad to catch this thief?
تريدين أن يقبض أبي على ذاك اللصّ إذاً؟
That's right!
!نعم
You know Beika Museum's exhibit of world-famous jewels?!
تعرفين أنّ متحف بيكا للفنون يعرض مجموعة من المجوهرات الشهيرة عالمياً الآن، صحيح؟
Daddy submitted our family gem, the lucky Black Star pearl,
بينها لؤلؤة النجم الأسود الجالبة للحظّ الحسن التي قدّمها أبي
and wants it protected
!وأريد حمايتها من قبضة كايتو 1412 الشرّيرة
Black Star
النجم الأسود
But why ask my dad and not the police?
لكن لمَ لا تطلبين من الشرطة بدلاً من أبي؟
We can't do that! The police would haul him off if they caught him!
لا ينفع! ستأخذه الشرطة فوراً إذا اعتقلته
But if your dad catches him, he might let us see his face!
لكن إذا أمسك به والدك، قد نستطيع !رؤية وجهه مباشرةً
His face?
وجهه؟
Yeah! Don't you wonder what he looks like?!
أجل! ألا يراودك الفضول حول ملامحه؟
# 1412 has the entire world going crazy!
!إنّه 1412، اللصّ الذي أثار الفوضى في العالم بأسره
I bet he's a fabulous guy!
!لا بدّ أنّه رجل بغاية الوسامة
Like Harrison Ford or John Lennon...
...مثل هاريسون فورد أو جون لينون
You live so happily...
يا لبساطتك
The light's green, Sonoko.
الإشارة خضراء يا سونوكو
Coming!
!حسناً
It'd be nice if he was like Brad Pitt!
سيكون من الرائع لو كان مثل براد بيت
Shinichi!
!شينتشي
Hey, now! The light's red!
!مهلك
But, that was Shinichi!
!لكن كان ذلك شينتشي
It was Shinichi...
...كان هناك
You sure it wasn't just a look-alike?
ألم يكن شخصاً يشبهه فحسب؟
You passed by Shinichi-niichan in Shibuya?!
!مررتِ بشينتشي-نيتشان في شيبويا؟
Yeah, right!
...مستحيل
It's true!
!إنّها الحقيقة
But he wouldn't respond! Isn't that horrible?!
لكنّه لم يكلّمني! أليس هذا فظيعاً؟
Hey, now! I wasn't in Shibuya!
!مهلك، لم أذهب لشيبويا
And besides, I haven't even changed bodies!
كما لم يرجع جسمي لطبيعته حتّى
Yeah, he's probably sick of you. Just forget about that mystery dweeb.
،لعلّه شعر بالملل منك فحسب انسي أمر مهووس التحرّي ذاك
Yeah... He was walking with a girl, too...
صحيح... كانت رفقته فتاة أيضاً
It was someone else! Don't worry about it!
!كان شخصاً آخر بالتأكيد! لا تقلقي
What?
ماذا؟
Anyway, do they really want me to catch this Kaitou something-or-other?
بأيّ حال، هل ما قلتِه قبلاً صحيح؟
Kaitou #1412!
!كايتو 1412
What's with the 1412?
ما خطب رقم 1412؟
No one's really sure where it comes from.
لا أحد يعرف أساس ذلك
According to Sonoko, he steals art and jewels from all over the world,
وفقاً لسونوكو، فهو لصٌّ شهير يسرق القطع الفنّية والمجوهرات حول العالم
and his top secret FBI or CIA
واجتمعت المباحث الفيدرالية ومنظمة الاستخبارات الأمريكية
or Interpol number was 1412.
والشرطة العالمية على ترميزه بالرقم السرّي 1412
"International Criminal Number"
الرقم الإجراميّ العالمي
The leading theory is that people learned the number and it just stuck!
يُقال أنّ ذاك الرقم تسرّب للناس وأصبحوا يطلقونه عليه
Sounds fake to me.
رائحة كذب كبير
Apparently he has a different name in Japan, though.
لكن يبدو أنّ له لقباً مختلفاً في اليابان
It's probably just word play.
مجرّد تلاعب لفظيّ حتماً
Like "The Crazy Thief" or something.
مثل "اللصّ المخبول"، فـ 412 يمكن أن تُقرأ "لصّ" بالإنجليزية بينما تشتق "المخبول" من 1
I don't think it was anything that old man-like.
لا أظنّه كان لقباً يصدر من رجال مُسنّين هكذا
How dumb. Who cares about some thief?
يا للسخافة، لستُ مهتماً بلصّ
I'm going to bed.
سأخلد للنوم
Oh, yeah. I have a copy of a weird warning letter
صحيح، أعطتني سونوكو نسخةً من رسالة إخطار غريبة
that Kaitou #1412 sent to Sonoko's house.
أرسلها كايتو 1412 لمنزلها
A weird warning letter?
رسالة إخطار غريبة؟
It doesn't make any sense! It's like a code!
لا يمكن فهمها أبداً، إنّها أشبه بالشفرة
"April Fools.
،كذبة إبريل"
When the moon splits the two, I shall enter upon waves
عندما يقسم القمر الشيئين، سآتي على الأمواج
in the name of the black star.
باسم النجم الأسود
Kaitou..."
"...كايتو
It's torn here...
الباقي مُمزق
Yeah, Sonoko's father tore it up in anger when it arrived
ليس باليد حيلة، قام والد سونوكو بتمزيقها في غضبه عندما وصلته
then taped it back together.
فلم يكن أمامه سوى لصقها معاً
Still, this makes no sense at all.
إنّها رسالة غريبة بحق
All I do get is that "April Fools" means he'll show up on April 1st...
ما فهمته هو "كذبة إبريل"، أي أنّه سيأتي في اليوم الأوّل من إبريل
Hey! I thought you went to bed!
أنت! ألم تكن ستنام؟
Lemme see...
...دعني أرى
Conan-kun?
كونان-كن؟
Beika Museum, 1:42 PM, March 31st
مارس 31، متحف بيكا للفنون الساعة 1:42 ظهراً
Wow...
مُذهل
It's like all the police in Tokyo have been mobilized...
كأنّ قوّات شرطة طوكيو كلّها قد نُشرت
I guess he really is a big international thief!
يبدو أنّه لصّ من طراز عالميّ حقّاً
All that work and I still didn't break the code...
لم أستطع حلّ هذه الرموز أبداً في النهاية
Detective Mori!
!متحرّي موري
Thank you for coming!
!شكراً على قدومك
I truly appreciate your listening to my daughter!
!أقدّر كثيراً إصغاءك لابنتي
We're 100-men strong with
وجود متحرّ مثلك هنا كامتلاك
Suzuki Shiro (51)
(51) سوزوكي شيرو رئيس مجموعة سوزوكي المالية
a detective like you here!
!قوّة مئة رجل
We're counting on you, Detective Mori!
!أتطلّع للكثير منك يا متحرّي موري
It's just one measly thief. I'll capture him with no trouble at all!
إنّه مجرّد لصٍّ بسيط، سأقبض عليه دون أيّ عناء
Sure you will! You haven't even cracked the code yet!
كلامٌ كبير وأنت لم تفكّك رموز الرسالة حتّى
So this is the largest black pearl in the world, the Black Star?
هذه أكبر لؤلؤة سوداء في العالم إذاً، النجم الأسود؟
Yes. The Suzuki family has been blessed with prosperity
أجل، نعمت عائلة سوزوكي بالازدهار
ever since my grandfather first purchased it.
مُذ اقتناها جدّي
It's the family's guardian angel.
إنّها أشبه بملاك العائلة الحارس
Security sure is tight for the day before the theft.
الحراسة مُشدّدة مع أنّنا في اليوم الذي يسبق عمليّة السرقة
Yes. All we got from the letter was the date.
نعم، بما أنّنا لم نستطع حلّ شيء من الرموز
I'm told that security will be on full detail starting tonight--
ستشدّد الشرطة تأهّبها بدءاً من مساء اليوم وفقما أخبروني
there's no telling from when or where Kaitou #1412 will strike.
فلا نعلم متى ومن أين سيأتي كايتو 1412
What?!
!ماذا؟
I already told you! The river! Deploy men along the river bank!
أخبرتكم! النهر! انشروا رجالاً !على ضفّة النهر، مفهوم؟
Kaitou #1412 plans to sneak inside
ينوي كايتو 1412 التسلّل للمتحف
Chaki Shintaro (49)
(49) تشاكي شينتارو رئيس فرقة التحقيق الثانية بمركز الشرطة
from the nearby Teimuzu River!
!عبر نهر تيموزو المجاور
You cracked the code?
حللت الرموز؟
Sure did!
نعم
The "enter upon waves" bit refers to the Teimuzu River!
سآتي على الأمواج" في الرسالة تعني" !أنّه سيسلك نهر تيموزو
The Teimuzu River is the only place in the vicinity with waves!
نهر تيموزو هو المكان الوحيد !في الجوار بأمواج
You're sloppy, Commissioner!
هذا ساذج سيّدي الرئيس
What?!
ماذا؟
Don't you get it? "Waves" means the ocean, which means "oki" (coast).
ألا تفهم؟ الأمواج تعني المحيط (والذي من مرادفاته "أوكي" (ساحل
And "star" means a pop star!
!بينما النجم يعني النجم الفنّان
In other words, the idol star who performs live tomorrow
أي أنّ هذا يشير للنجمة الفنّانة التي ستؤدي في حفلٍ غداً
at the nearby Beika Town Hall, Okino Yoko-chan!
!في قاعة بيكا العامة، أوكينو يوكو-تشان
What's more, her last song will be "Moon Lady"!
إضافةً لذلك، الأغنية التي تختم بها "ستكون "سيّدة القمر
"When the moon splits the two" means that...
...عندما يقسم القمر الشيئين" تعني"
...Kaitou #1412 will come from the vicinity of Beika Town Hall
أنّ كايتو 1412 سيأتي من قاعة بيكا
when the show ends at 9:00 pm!
!عندما ينتهي العرض في التاسعة مساءً
Whatever you say...
...يا للسخافة
Yes, that does make sense.
نعم، كلامك منطقيّ
Well done, Detective Mori!
!مُبهر أيّها المتحرّي موري
Hey, now...
...مهلكم
Alright! Have Teams C through E assemble near Beika Town Hall!
حسنٌ، لتجتمع الفرق من ج إلى هـ !عند مسرح بيكا العام فوراً
Yes, sir!
!حاضر
Hey!
...لحظة
Still, I haven't broken the code either...
مع ذلك، لم أستطع حلّ الرموز بعد
Say, where's the fellow who was transferred to us last month?
أتتم، أين ذهب ذاك الرجل الذي انتقل لنا الشهر الفائت؟
The inspector? He took some officers somewhere this morning...
إذا تقصد المفتّش فقد أخذ أتباعه لمكان ما هذا الصباح
What's he thinking?!
!ما الذي يفكّر به؟ في هذا الوقت الحرج
Anyway, it's 2:00! Why don't we have lunch nearby?
.بأيّ حال سيّدي الرئيس، أصبحت الساعة الثانية فما رأيك بأكل الغداء في الجوار؟
Are you guys gonna have lunch?
هل تريدون أكل الغداء يا ران؟
We ate on the way here...
أكلنا في طريقنا
Eat?
أكل؟
Wait a minute! Could it be?!
!لحظة، أيمكن؟
Conan-kun! Where are you going?
كونان-كن، أين تذهب؟
What are you doing, Conan-kun?
ما الذي تفعله يا كونان-كن؟
Checking the direction with my watch.
أتفقّد الاتجاه بساعتي
The direction?
الاتّجاه؟
Yeah. First, you point the hour hand toward the sun.
نعم، أوجّه عقرب الساعات نحو الشمس أوّلاً
Japan's in the northern hemisphere, so halfway between it and 12
تقع اليابان في النصف الشمالي للكرة الأرضيّة
I was just testing something Shinichi-niichan told me, of course!
هـ-هذا شيءٌ سمعته من شينتشي-نيتشان !وأردت تجربته لا أكثر بالطبع
Which means south is at 1 o'clock, and southeast at 2:30!
،ما يعني أنّ الجنوب عند اتّجاه الساعة الواحدة والجنوب الشرقيّ عند الثانية والنصف
Aha! I've figured you out, Kaitou #1412!
!فهمت، حللتُ لغزك يا كايتو 1412
11:04 PM, March 31st
مارس 31 الساعة 11:04 ليلاً
Fast asleep!
تغطّ في النوم
Agasa here.
أجل، معك آغاسا
Oh, Shinichi! Eh? What?
!شينتشي
You want me to find out about Kaitou #1412?
تريد منّي التحرّي عن كايتو 1412؟
Please, Professor. He should be in my dad's crime files.
أرجوك يا بروفسور، يُفترض أنّه موجود في ملفّ الجرائم الذي يملكه أبي
But what do you need it for?
لكن لمَ تحتاج ذلك؟
I want to know about him before I meet him!
!أريد التعرّف عليه قبل أن أذهب للقائه
Meet him?! You know where he is?!
!للقائه؟ تعرف أين هو؟
Yup! I've figured out his route inside!
نعم، اكتشفتُ الطريق الذي سيسلكه للداخل
Then why didn't you tell the police?!
لمَ لم تخبر الشرطة إذاً؟
I suddenly wanna see it, too...
أصبحتُ أريد لقاءه وجهاً لوجه بدوري
...the face of a retro thief who sends warning notices in this day and age!
وأرى وجه اللصّ قديم الطراز الذي يرسل !إخطارات قبل جريمته في هذا العصر
The "two" in "when the moon splits the two"
...الشيئان اللذان سيقسمهما القمر
refers to a satellite and the sun!
!هما القمر الاصطناعي والشمس
And if the splitting refers to the moon creating an eclipse between them...
وإذا كان المقصود بالقسم هو دخول القمر ...بين الشمس والقمر الصناعي، فالكسوف
...then he'll show up between 12:30 and 4:00 am when BS TV is off!
عندها سيأتي بين 12:30 و4:00 صباحاً "عندما ينتهي بثّ قناة "بي إس
Yes! The Black Star's initials are BS (Broadcast Satellite)!
أجل، الحرفان الأوليّان لعبارة النجم الأسود (في الإنجليزية هما "بي" و"إس" (قمر البثّ
If the "waves" refer to a satellite signal...
إذا كان المقصود بالأمواج هي الموجات ...الكهرومغناطيسية للقمر الصناعي
...then he'll be coming from the direction of the BS signal!
!"إذاً سيأتي من اتّجاه إشارة "بي إس
The BS signal is sent from south to west at a 45 degree angle
تُرسل إشارة "بي إس" من الجنوب للغرب بزاوية 45 درجة
and from 42.3 degrees above the horizon.
وبـ 42.3 درجة فوق مستوى سطح البجر
The only place that fits the bill is the roof of the Haido City Hotel!
المكان الوحيد الذي يطابق المواصفات ...ويطلّ على متحف بيكا
Nothing. There's only one person I'm after.
دعوه وشأنه، هدفنا شخص واحد فحسب
And not even he could dress up as a child.
وحتّى هو لا يستطيع التنكّر كطفل
Employees Only
للموظفين فقط
Beika Museum is... right around there.
...متحف بيكا
12:28.
الثانية عشرة وثمان وعشرون دقيقة
Now I just wait for him to show up...
ما تبقّى هو انتظار قدومه هنا فحسب
Hello? Professor?
مرحباً؟ بروفسور؟
Hi, Shinichi.
شينتشي
I checked your dad's files with recent newspaper articles.
طابقتُ ملفات والدك مع المقالات في الصحف مؤخراً
Kaitou #1412 is enveloped in quite a bit of mystery.
كايتو 1412 هو شخص مغلّف بالغموض
His first appearance was in Paris eighteen years ago.
ظهر لأوّل مرّة في باريس قبل 18 عاماً
He suddenly disappeared ten years later and was presumed dead,
اختفى بعد مرور 10 أعوام فجأةً، وشاع أنّه مات
but he's back after eight years and is primarily active in Japan.
لكنّه رجع بعد ثمانية أعوام الآن ويركّز نشاطه في اليابان
Eighteen years ago? He must be pretty old then...
قبل 18 عاماً؟ لا بدّ أنّه كبير في السنّ إذاً
He has all kinds of names...
...ألقابه كثيرة
"The Modern Lupin," "The Moonlight Magician"...
..."لوبان العصر الحديث"، "ساحر ضوء القمر"
But there's one alias that people like the most...
لكن هناك لقب شعبيّ يتداوله الناس أكثر من غيره
Alias?
لقب شعبيّ؟
A young novelist interested in the crafty Kaitou #1412
أثار تلاعب كايتو 1412 بأفراد الشرطة كما لو كان
once jokingly read the number like so...
...فتلاعب برقم 1412 ليُقرأ هكذا
"K I D."
"كي آي دي"
"K I D"?
كي آي دي"؟"
That's right. Kaitou #1412 is known as...
نعم، ما يطلقه الناس ...على كايتو 1412 هو
...the Kaitou Kid!
!كايتو كيد
He landed silently before me,
،كيلا يعكّر سكون الليل
so as not to disturb the stillness of the night.
هبط بجناحَي الصمت أمامي
Together with a fearless smile,
،مُبدياً ابتسامةً جريئة
as if he saw through everything.
كما لو أنّها تنبّأت بكلّ شيء
What's going on, Shinichi? Shin--
ما الخطب يا شينشي؟
A cape and a silk hat...
حرملة وقبّعة حريرية
An impenetrable stance...
...وضعيّة بلا فجوات
I can't make out his face, but he's surprisingly young.
لا أستطيع رؤية ملامحه بوضوح من العدسة والإنارة الضعيفة، لكنّه يافع لحدٍّ مُفاجئ
His thirties. Twenties? No, even younger!
في ثلاثينياته؟ عشرينياته؟
Hey, little boy.
مرحباً يا فتى
What are you doing up here?
ماذا تفعل في هذا المكان؟
Fireworks!
!ألعاب نارية
What?!
!ماذا؟
A strange flash and sound?!
!وميض غريب وصوت؟
Yes. Above the Haido City Hotel, southwest of the museum.
نعم، فوق فندق مدينة هايدو جنوب غرب المتحف
Shall I check it out, Commissioner?
هل أذهب للتفقّد سيّدي الرئيس؟
Of course you shall!
!بالطبع
Look! A helicopter! I think it noticed!
!انظر! مروحيّة! يبدو أنّهم انتبهوا لنا
Seems you're no ordinary kid.
يبدو أنّك لست صبيّاً عادياً يا فتى
I'm Edogawa Conan. A detective.
أنا إيدوغاوا كونان، مُتحرٍّ
Shouldn't you be escaping, Kaitou Kid-san?
أليس عليك التصرّف يا كايتو كيد-سان؟
I only have one chance to get him with my tranquilizer gun!
لدي فرصة واحدة فقط لإصابته بالإبرة المخدّرة
The instant he turns away to escape!
!حالما يلتفت للهرب
A radio?!
إذاعة؟
Chaki here! Kaitou Kid sighted on top of the Haido City Hotel!
هذا تشاكي، شُوهد كايتو كيد فوق !سطح فندق مدينة هايدو
Attention all patrol cars in Beika and Haido
نداء لكلّ عربات الحراسة في بيكا وهايدو
and all helicopters in the air above Beika!
وللمروحيّات المحلّقة فوق بيكا
Proceed to the scene at once and capture the Kaitou Kid!
!توجّهوا للساحة فوراً واقبضوا على كايتو كيد
He's using my voice!
!إ-إنّه يستعمل صوتي
Wait! That's not me!
!انتظروا! ذلك ليس أنا
It's his trap! All units, return at once!
!هذا فخّه! لكلّ الوحدات، ارجعوا فوراً
This is Helicopter #1! I'm above the hotel!
هنا المروحيّة رقم 1، وصلتُ فندق مدينة هايدو
Sighting confirmed!
!أرى شبيهاً لكيد
What?!
!ماذا؟
I think he sent the orders!
يبدو أنّه من أرسل الأوامر
This is Nakamori!
هذا أنا، ناكاموري
Attention all officers inside the Haido City Hotel!
نداء لكلّ الضبّاط في فندق مدينة هايدو
The Kid's on the roof! Rush to the scene at once! Seize him!
!كيد على السطح! أسرعوا للمكان فوراً واعتقلوه
This guy's incredible...
...إ-إنّه مذهل
He can imitate any voice without a machine!
!يقلّد عدّة أصوات دون استعمال أداة حتّى
Damn it!
!تبّاً
Your voice is on the radio!
!صـ-صوتك على الإذاعة سيّدي المفتّش
lt's the Kid! He's using my
إنّه كيد! يستعمل صوتي
Nakamori Ginzo (41)
(41) ناكاموري غينزو مفتّش في فرقة التحقيق الثانية بمركز الشرطة
voice to bring us to him!
!كي يستدرجنا له
That's insane! Why on earth would he do that?!
!سـ-سخافة! ماذا سيجني من فعله هذا؟
What's he doing?!
!ما الذي يفعله؟
Satisfied, Detective?
رضيت الآن أيّها المتحرّي الصغير؟
Freeze, Kid!
!مكانك يا كيد
Oh, my. Inspector Nakamori. You certainly arrived quickly.
عجباً، مفتّش ناكاموري! وصلتَ سريعاً
Ha! You knew I cracked your code and had the place staked out!
ما الذي تقوله؟ تعرف أنّي حللت رموز رسالتك وكنتُ أراقب هذا المكان
I figured you might hang-glide in, so I checked everyone in the hotel
،توقّعتُ أن تغادر من هنا بطائرتك الشراعية ففتّشت الجميع في الفندق
and fortified the main entrance,
وشدّدت حراسة المدخل الأمامي
but I never expected you to go around Toto Tower and then land here.
لكن لم يخطر لي أنّك ستستدير من برج توتو وتهبط هنا
Forget about the pearl! You have nowhere to run!
!انسَ أمر اللؤلؤة! لا مهرب لك
I'm only here to observe you tonight. I don't plan to steal anything.
أتيتُ الليلة لمراقبتكم فحسب، لا أنوي سرقة شيء
What?!
ماذا؟
Oh? I clearly wrote so at the start of the letter!
توقّعتُ أنّي ذكرت الأمر في بداية الرسالة
"April Fools." It was a lie!
كذبة أبريل"، أي كانت كذبة"
Don't let him escape! Get him!
!لا-لا تدعوه يهرب! حاصروه
A flash grenade!
!قنبلة ضوئية
Are you aware, little boy?
أتعرف يا فتى؟
A kaitou is a creative artist who skillfully steals his prey,
اللصّ هو فنّان مُبدع يسرق فريسته بحرفيّة
but a detective is nothing more than a critic
لكنّ المتحري ليس أكثر من ناقد
who finds fault in what is left behind!
يتفحّص البقايا ويبحث عن عيوب
What?!
!ماذا؟
He disappeared!
!اختفى
He vanished!
!لقد اختفى
Helicopters! Track him using radar!
!يا قائدي المروحيّات، استعملوا الرادار! لاحقوه به
It only shows our three helicopters in the area!
!لا يُظهر سوى مروحيّاتنا الثلاث في المنطقة
Has he gotten away again?!
أهرب مُجدداً؟
This is insane! No one can just disappear like that!
لا يُعقل! لا يمكن أن يختفي !إنسان بهذه السهولة
What's this?!
...هـ-هذه
"On March 19th, I will appear on the Queen Selizabeth
في التاسع عشر من أبريل، سأظهر على" متن الملكة سيليزابيث
leaving from Yokohama Port to steal the real Black Star.
التي ستُبحر من ميناء يوكوهاما لسرقة النجم الأسود الحقيقيّ
--Kaitou Kid"
"كايتو كيد-
March 19th --Queen Selizabeth, Yokohama Port
أبريل 19 الملكة سيليزابيث، ميناء يوكوهاما
Please cancel it, Commissioner Chaki!
!ألغها رجاءً سيّدي الرئيس
We're dealing with the Kaitou Kid!
!نحن نتعامل مع كايتو كيد
We can't let him get near the jewel with such lousy security as that!
لا يمكننا تركه يقترب من الجوهرة !مع حراسة ضعيفة كهذه
Don't be like that, Nakamori-kun!
هوّن عليك يا ناكاموري-كن
Tonight's party is full of important people!
قائمة حضور حفلة اليوم تعجّ بالشخصيات المرموقة
We can't do anything rough!
لا يمكننا التعامل بخشونة
Besides, we'll lose face if we cancel the party out of fear of him!
كما أنّ سمعتنا ستتلطخ إذا ألغينا الحفلة خوفاً من كايتو كيد
Don't worry. It'll take three hours for the ship to get to Tokyo.
لا تقلق، ستستغرق السفينة 3 ساعات للوصول لطوكيو من يوكوهاما
It's a floating prison! Even if he does get on, he's like a rat in a trap!
إنّها سجن عائم، حتّى لو تسلّل على متنها !سيكون مُحاصراً
This year marks Suzuki Industries' 60th anniversary.
دخلنا الذكرى الستّين لتأسّس شركة سوزوكي هذا العام
This is entirely because of the support from you all.
ذلك بفضل دعمكم جميعاً
Please forget about sneak thieves for tonight
انسوا أمر اللصّ الدنيء الليلة رجاءً
and enjoy this elegant and grand party to which 500 have been invited!
واستمتعوا بهذه الحفلة الراقية والفخمة التي تحتضن 500 مدعوّاً
But, first!
...قبل ذلك
I have devised a
جهّزتُ خطّةً خاصة لليلة
Suzuki Tomoko (43)
(43) سوزوكي توموكو أمّ سونوكو
Please open the small boxes given to you before you boarded.
فلتفتحوا الصناديق الصغيرة التي وُزّعت عليكم قبل صعودكم من فضلكم
They are my letter of challenge to any foolish thieves.
إنّها رسالة تحدٍّ منّي للصّ الساذج
This is--
...هـ-هذه
Yes! These are our family's symbol,
أجل! رمز عائلتنا
as well as the Kaitou Kid's prey tonight! The Black Star!
!وهدف كايتو كيد الليلة، النجم الأسود
Only one is real, of course. And only I know to whom it was given.
الحقيقيّة واحدة بالطبع، وأنا وحدي تعرف من أخذها
The rest are imitation pearls!
البقيّة مجرّد لآلئ مقلّدة
Now, then. Please put them on your chests
حسناً يا سادة، علّقوها على صدوركم رجاءً
and tell the Kid, "Go ahead and take it, if you dare"!
"ودعوا كيد يفهم، "تعال وخذها إذا استطعت
Of course, that's assuming he manages to determine which one is real
ذلك بافتراض أنّه سيستطيع تحديد الحقيقية بالطبع
during the three hours we're at sea!
!خلال الثلاث ساعات من إبحارنا
Your mom's pretty smart!
!أمّك مُبهرة
What's wrong, Sonoko?
ما الخطب يا سونوكو؟
I can't find my sister...
...لا أرى أختي
Don't tell me she's still at home!
أيمكن أنّها لا تزال في المنزل؟
Yeah, right!
مستحيل
Eh?! The ship already left?!
ماذا؟ أبحرت السفينة؟
Suzuki Residence
منزل سوزوكي
How come?!
كيف؟
That's my line! Do you know what time it is?!
!هذا كلامي! ما الساعة الآن برأيك؟
But the commissioner called to say he was delaying it two hours...
لكنّ الضابط اتّصل بنا وقال أنّ الإبحار سيتأخّر ساعتين
Right, Dad?
أليس كذلك يا أبي؟
Daddy's there?!
أبي عندك؟
Bastard!
!الوغد
Where did the company president go?!
أين ذهب رئيس الشركة الذي كان هنا؟
He went to the restroom...
لدورة المياه
Now I see! He got on board disguised as the president!
فهمت، صعد متنكراً بهيئة الرئيس
I thank you, Kaitou Kid!
شكراً يا كايتو كيد
You've given me a chance to tear off that bold mask of yours!
أعطيتني فرصةً قيّمة لانتزاع !قناعك الجريء ذاك
Eh?! Kaitou #1412 disguised himself as Daddy to get on the ship?!
ماذا؟ تنكّر كايتو 1412 بهيئة أبي !وصعد على متن السفينة؟
I just found his disguise and props in the bathroom!
وجدتُ في الحمّام ثياب والدك التي استعملها !بالإضافة لأدوات التنكّر
The officers are checking it now!
!رجال الشرطة يفحصونها الآن
But this is him. I doubt they'll find any evidence...
لكن بما أنّ هذا هو، فلن يجدوا أيّ دليل غالباً
Oh? Where's Ran-neechan?
ماذا؟ أين ران-نيتشان؟
Out looking for you, since you didn't come back.
ذهبت للبحث عنك بما أنّك لم ترجع
She was worried Kaitou #1412 had caught you.
كانت قلقةً من إمساك كايتو 1412 بك
It's not "#1412."
"ليس "1412
His name is Kaitou Kid! Get it right!
!اسمه كايتو كيد! ذلك مُربك فلا تخطئه رجاءً
Okay...
...حسناً
Who's he?
من ذاك الشخص؟
Inspector Nakamori. He works full-time pursuing the Kaitou Kid.
،المفتّش ناكاموري من مركز الشرطة يتمحور عمله حول ملاحقة كايتو كيد
Like you, he's a reliable knight we hired to protect the Black Star.
إنّه فارس أهلٌ للثقّة عيّنته عائلتنا لحماية النجم الأسود، مثلك تماماً
Still, Madam!
...لكن سيّدتي
All 500 people here are wearing black pearls!
كلّ الضيوف الخمسمئة الليلة يعلّقون اللؤلؤة السوداء على صدورهم
And except for the real one, they're all imitations!
!كما كلّها مقلّدة باستثناء الواحدة الحقيقية
I can't guard it unless I know which one is real...
...لا يمكنني حراستها دون أن تخبريني من يحملها
They all look alike, but they're still imitations.
حتّى لو كانت النُسخ متقنة الصنع، تبقى تقليداً
Close scrutiny could narrow it down a bit;
إذا أمعنتَ التدقيق ستقلّص الاحتمالات
among them are dull and dreary ones such as mine
بعضها باهتة وغير لامعة مثل التي معي
and excessively shiny rubbish such as yours.
والبعض الآخر مُفرطة اللمعان لحدٍّ يكشف رخصها مثل التي معك
But checking every person in this crowd would be...
...لكن تفقّد كل فرد من الضيوف سيكون
Then I'll give you a special hint.
سأعطيك تلميحاً خاصاً إذاً
The Black Star, the black pearl with a peacock-green luster
...النجم الأسود
that fascinated my grandfather sixty years ago,
الذي أسر جدّي قبل 60 عاماً
is with someone especially worthy of it.
هي بحوزة أكثر شخص موافق لها
Worthy?!
موافق؟
Coincidentally, that someone is one out of five hundred...
يُصادف أنّ ذاك الذي يطابق المواصفات واحد بين خمسمئة
It must be a woman, if the jewel suits them...
لا بدّ أن تكون امرأة إذا كانت الجوهرة تلائمها
Oh, but it suits you, too, Mori-san!
!لكنّها تلائمك أيضاً يا موري-سان
Oh, so it is you!
!كان أنت بالفعل يا موري-سان
lt's good to see you again!
!مضى وقتٌ طويل
Hatamoto Joji (41)
(41) هاتاموتو جوجي طاهٍ في مطعم وجبات فرنسية
Thank you for your help a while back!
!شكراً على مساعدتك في السابق
Aren't you the Hatamoto Group's--
ألستَ من مجموعة هاتاموتو؟
Yes! Thanks to this fine woman and the president,
بلى، تمكنتُ من فتح المزيد من المطاعم
I've opened up more restaurants!
!بفضل سيّدتي هنا والرئيس
In fact, tonight's meal is my own--
...في الواقع، وجبة الليلة من إعدادي
So sorry, Joji-san.
يا للأسف يا جوجي-سان
Seems Mr. Suzuki won't be there,
يبدو أنّ الرئيس سوزوكي
Mifune Takuya (26)
(26) ميفوني تاكويا رئيس شركة ميفوني للإلكترونيات
thanks to the Kaitou Kid.
ليس موجوداً بسبب كايتو كيد
Your flattery food will go to waste!
مائدة التملّق التي أعددتَها ستُهدر
You're as reprehensible as ever!
!تحبّ المشاحنة كعادتك
Nothing of the sort!
البتّة
The guy from the Yotsui girl's birthday party...
الشاب من حفلة عيد ميلاد ...الآنسة الثريّة يوتسوي
Oh? You're not wearing yours?
ماذا؟ لا ترتدي لؤلؤتك؟
I hate childish games like this.
أكره هذه الألعاب الطفوليّة
But you'll seem suspicious if you don't wear it.
لكن ستكون تحت الشُبهة إذا لم ترتدها
Fine.
ليس بيدي حيلة
Eh? Ayako-san isn't here?
ماذا؟ لم تأت أياكو-سان؟
No, she couldn't make it...
...كلا، وقع التباسٌ ما
Tomizawa Yuzo (28)
(28) توميزاوا يوزو خطيب أخت سونوكو
Oh. That's too bad...
فهمت، هذا مؤسف
This is the Suzuki Industries party, all right.
كما تتوقّع من حفلة لشركة سوزوكي
It's teeming with rich kids and company presidents.
تعجّ بالأبناء الأثرياء ورؤساء الشركات
Ran's taking a long time...
...تأخّرت ران تلك
She's probably lost somewhere! Ran has no sense of direction!
لعلّها ضلّت في مكانٍ ما، فلا حسّ بالاتجاه لديها
Who has no sense of direction?!
!لا حسّ اتّجاه لديّ؟
Oh, Ran! I didn't see you there!
ماذا؟ كنتِ هنا؟
I'm Police Commissioner Chaki!
أنا رئيس الشرطة تشاكي
You may have already heard,
لعلّ بينكم من سمع بالأمر سلفاً
but that pesky villain has somehow boarded the ship!
لكن يبدو أنّ ذاك المجرم المزعج قد تسلّل لمتن السفينة
As you know, he's a master of disguise!
كما تعلمون، إنّه أستاذ في التنكّر
He possesses an immeasurable evil talent that he uses
يمتلك موهبةً شريرة لا حدود لها
to learn about his target and fully imitate them,
يستعملها في دراسة هدفه وتعلّم محاكاته تماماً
even down to their face, voice, and personality!
!بما في ذلك وجهه وصوته وشخصيّته
He may even be among you already!
!قد يكون بينكم بالفعل
Normally, we would carefully inspect each and every person,
،كنّا لنفتّش كل شخص في العادة
but we'll refrain from such incivility here.
لكن سنمتنع من هذه المضايقة لأجواء الحفلة
Passwords!
!كلمات سرّ
Pair up with the person next to you and decide on a password!
شكّل ثنائياً مع الشخص بجوارك !واتّفق معه على كلمة سرّ رجاءً
I get it! That way he can't keep disguising himself,
فهمت! لا يمكنه تغيير تنكّره باستمرار هكذا
which will allow the police to single him out!
!فتستطيع الشرطة تحديده
What should our password be?
أيّ كلمة سرّ سنختار؟
OK, when I say "Holmes"...
..."حسناً، عندما أقول "هولمز
...I'll say "Lupin"!
!أقول "لوبان" إذاً
What're you doing, Power Room?!
!ما الذي تفعلونه يا غرفة الطاقة؟
No, this is--
...كلا سيّدي المفتّش، هذا
Kaitou Kid!
!كايتو كيد
Your passwords are pointless.
لا فائدة من كلمات السرّ
What?!
!ماذا؟
The Black Star is already in my hands.
النجم الأسود بيدي سلفاً
Impossible!
!مـ-مستحيل
Oh, dear. It's the pesky thief.
عجباً، يا للصّ المزعج
I'll just have to punish this scheming boy.
لا بدّ من مُعاقبة هذا المشاغب المُحبّ للألعاب
Mom!
!أمّي
What have you done?!
ما الذي فعلتِه؟
There's no need to worry, Inspector. After all...
...لا تقلق حضرة المفتّش، فهو
...he's still alive!
لا يزال حيّاً
My guards caught him in the tablecloth
أمسكه حرّاسنا بغطاء المائدة
after I pretended to shoot him with this model gun.
بعدما تظاهرتُ بالإطلاق عليه من هذا المسدّس المُقلّد
Yes. He's a brilliant magician I hired as entertainment...
نعم، إنّه ساحر عبقريّ عيّنته الليلة للترفيه
Sanada Kazumi (27) - Magician
!سانادا كازومي-كن
...Sanada Kazumi-kun!
(سانادا كازومي (27 ساحر
Let's give him a round of applause for acting out
يا سادة، هلّا صفّقنا له بحرارة
the Kaitou Kid's pitiable end for us!
لتمثيله المُتقن لنهاية كايتو كيد البائسة؟
I see. Kaitou Kid is an expert magician-- the perfect role for you.
.فهمت، كايتو كيد ساحر بارع فهذا دور مثاليّ لك
Artists?!
فنّانان؟
Now, then! Please come to the stage!
إذاً يا سادة، تعالوا قرب المسرح رجاءً
I'll show you some of my magic!
!سأريكم بعضاً من سحري
but a detective is nothing more than a critic
لكنّ المتحري ليس أكثر من ناقد
They all seem suspicious!
!كلّهم أصبحوا يبدون مثيرين للريبة
There's what she said...
...ما قالته أمّ سونوكو
The black pearl is with someone especially worthy of it.
اللؤلؤة السوداء بحوزة أكثر شخص لائق بها
If only I knew what that meant!
...إذا فهمتُ ما قصدتَه على الأقل
I apologize!
!آ-آسف
That's all right! Spilled cards won't ruin my luck (tsuki).
لا بأس، سقوط البطاقات لن يعني سقوط القمر الذي يشعّ بحظّي
Moon (tsuki)?
القمر(تسكي)؟
Say, didn't you have a list of everyone at this party?
أليست معك لائحة حضور هذه الحفلة يا عمّ؟
Yeah...
بلى
Can I see it?
هلّا أريتني إيّاها؟
This? Here.
هذه؟ هاك
Here you are!
هاك
Thank you, ladies!
شكراً يا آنستيّ
Let me give you a card in return!
سأعطيكما بطاقةً في المقابل
Are you sure?!
حقّاً؟
Wait! First, let me use my X-ray eye to read your minds
مهلك! دعيني أستعمل أشعّتي السينية لقراءة أفكاركما
and predict your card!
!والتنبّؤ بالبطاقة
I'm so excited!
!أشعر بإثارة
Yeah!
!نعم
Now I see!
فهمت
That's why he said that in the 2nd letter!
لذا قال ذلك في رسالته الثانية
I've figured it out, Kaitou Kid!
فهمت يا كايتو كيد
The location of your prey, that is!
!أعرف مكان فريستك التي تستهدفها
A pigeon (hato)? Hato? Heart?
حمامة؟ هاتو؟ قلب؟
The Ace of Hearts, then!
!ستكون آص القلوب إذاً
Please pick any card you wish!
هيّا، اسحبا أيّ بطاقة تريدان من فضلكما
Ran! The right! The right one!
!ران! اليُمنى! اختاري اليُمنى
"As Caesar was with Cleopatra, I am already by your side.
،كما كان قيصر مولعاً بكليوباترا" أنا بجانبك بالفعل
- Kaitou Kid"
"كايتو كيد-
The Kid!
!كيد
He's here!
!لقد ظهر
Calm down, everyone! Confirm your passwords!
!اهدؤوا جميعاً! تحقّقوا من كلمات السرّ رجاءً
Hey! Nakamori-kun! Don't tell me it's already been stolen!
ناكاموري-كن! لا تخبرني !أنّ اللؤلؤة سُرقت بالفعل
No, he doesn't have it yet, nor has he escaped!
لم يأخذها بعد، ولم يهرب أيضاً
He's simply confusing us to make things work his way!
!يحاول إرباكنا كي يتلاعب بنا
Don't worry, we can catch him! He's not a wizard!
لا تقلقوا، يمكننا القبض عليه! فهو ليس ساحراً
He's a human being who relies on tricks!
إنّه بشريّ يعتمد على الحيل فحسب
Kaitou Kid really left a message?!
رسالة من كايتو كيد حقّاً؟
Yep! It was on the card Ran just picked!
نعم! كانت على البطاقة !التي اختارتها ران
But when and how did he put this in there?!
لكن كيف ومتى أضافها؟
The Kid is crafty! Everything about him is a mystery!
كيد مراوغ، كلّ ما يتعلّق به غامض
All we know is that he's somewhere in here!
ما نعلمه يقيناً هو أنّه بيننا بالفعل
Please calm down, everyone!
!الزموا الهدوء جميعاً
Does that mean he knows where the real pearl is?!
أيمكن أنّه يعرف أين اللؤلؤة الحقيقية؟
Even if he did, this is a floating prison.
حتّى لو عرف، هذا سجنٌ عائم
Could he possibly make off with the Black Star
أيمكنه سرقة النجم الأسود والهرب
with this police presence?
مع تواجد الشرطة المكثّف حقّاً؟
Inspector! We'll arrive in Tokyo Harbor in thirty minutes!
حضرة المفتّش، سنصل مرفأ طوكيو !بعد 30 دقيقة
Alright! Seal all the exits! Let no one outside!
!حسنٌ، أقفلوا كلّ مخارج القاعة !لا تسمحوا لأحد بالخروج
Time to show yourself, Kaitou Kid!
أظهر حركتك يا كايتو كيد
This is your only chance to strike while everyone's restless!
إذا كنتَ ستقوم بشيء، فهذه فرصتك !مع توتّر الضيوف
Hey, Ran! Where'd your pearl go?!
ر-ران! أين ذهبت لؤلؤتك؟
Eh?! No way!
!ماذا؟ مُحال
Excuse me! Could someone pick up that pearl?
المعذرة! أيمكن لأحد حمل تلك اللؤلؤة؟
What the...
!ماذا؟
The pearl! It exploded!
!اللؤلؤة! اللؤلؤة انفجرت
Don't tell me the Kid rigged them!
...أ-أيمكن أنّ كيد فخّخها
Forget this!
!لا تعبثوا معي
I'm not wearing this thing!
!لن أرتدي هذه
Mom!
!أمّي
Are you all right?!
أأنتِ بخير؟
Open the door this instant!
!افتح الباب بسرعة
Huh?! Your pearl is gone, too!
!ماذا؟ اختفت لؤلؤتك أيضاً يا أمّي
Inspector! We can't hold them back!
!حـ-حضرة المفتّش! لا نستطيع صدّهم أكثر
Yes, sir!
!حاضر
Ran-neechan! Let's go catch him, too!
!ران-نيتشان! لنذهب للإمساك به بدورنا
Wait, Conan-kun!
!ا-انتظر يا كونان-كن
I know who the Kaitou Kid is!
!عرفتُ هويّة كايتو كيد
A letter declaring the upcoming theft of the Suzuki family's Black Star
وصلت رسالة إخطار بسرقة مُقبلة ،للنجم الأسود، جوهرة عائلة سوزوكي
arrived at Sonoko's house.
لمنزل سونوكو
The sender was one Kaitou Kid.
كان المُرسل كايتو كيد
Upon cracking his code, I waited for him atop the Haido City Hotel.
بعد حلّي لألغاز الرسالة، انتظرتُه وحدي على سطح فندق مدينة هايدو
He landed silently before me
هبط بصمتٍ أمامي
so as not to disturb the stillness of the night.
كيلا يعكّر سكون الليل
I only had one chance to use my tranquilizer gun!
كانت لديّ فرصة واحدة فحسب !لاستعمال الإبرة المخدّرة
The instant he turned away to escape!
!لحظة استدارته والهرب
But instead of running, he imitated multiple voices without a machine
لكن بدل الهرب، قلّد أصوات عدّة أشخاص دون استعمال أداة
to lure the police in, and then vanished like smoke!
!واستدرج الشرطة، ثمّ اختفى أمامنا كالدخان
All that remained was another letter.
كلّ ما تبقّى هي رسالة إخطار أخرى
Against Inspector Nakamori's protests,
،رغم معارضة المفتّش ناكاموري
the Suzuki Industries' 60th anniversary boat party began as scheduled.
أقامت شركة سوزوكي حفلة الذكرى الستّين على السفينة وفق المُخطط
Sonoko's mother, Suzuki Tomoko, devised a plan
،ابتكرت أمّ سونوكو، سوزوكي توموكو
that looked to spell failure for the Kaitou Kid,
خطّةً بدا أنّها ستفسد سعي كايتو كيد
but he blew up the pearls and stole the Black Star during the confusion!
لكنّه فجّر اللآلئ وسرق النجم الأسود !ببراعة أثناء الفوضى
I've figured out who you are, Kaitou Kid!
!اكتشفتُ هويّتك يا كايتو كيد
What?! You didn't find the Kid?!
!ماذا؟! لم تجدوا كيد؟
No. We checked all the passengers who left the room earlier, but...
كلا، فتّشنا كلّ الركّاب الذين ...خرجوا من القاعة قبل قليل، لكن
He has to be on board still! Check every last person on the ship!
!لا يزال على متن السفينة بلا شكّ !فلتفتّشوا كلّ الخمسمئة راكب فرداً فرداً
Yes, sir!
!حاضر
But how did he know she was wearing the real Black Star?!
لكن كيف عرف كيد أنّ النجم الأسود الحقيقيّ هو الذي ترتديه السيّدة؟
This is the engine room, Conan-kun!
!نحن في غرفة المحرّكات يا كونان-كن
Is the Kaitou Kid really in here?
هل يوجد كايتو كيد هنا حقّاً؟
Say, Ran-neechan. Do you know about the language of jewels?
أخبريني يا ران-نيتشان، هل تعرفين لغة الجواهر؟
The language of jewels?
لغة الجواهر؟
A pearl means "moon" or "woman."
"اللؤلؤة تعني "القمر"، أو "امرأة
Of the passengers on board, the only woman with moons in her name
بين ركّاب السفينة، المرأة الوحيدة التي كان رمز القمر في اسمها
is Suzuki Tomoko-san.
هي سوزوكي توموكو-سان فحسب
In other words, she had the real one!
أي كانت اللؤلؤة الحقيقية معها
But how does that tell you who the Kid is?
لكن كيف عرفت هويّة كيد من ذلك؟
The cards!
!البطاقات
You know how the card you chose had his message?
ألم تكن رسالة كيد على البطاقة التي اخترتِها؟
Yeah...
بلى
It's a basic trick in which the magician used the pigeon in his right hand
سرّ تلك الحيلة يكمن في لفت انتباه المشاهدين للحمامة في يده اليمنى
to distract the audience while he switched decks in his left hand.
بينما يبدّل مجموعة البطاقات بيده اليسرى
...does that mean Kaitou Kid was that magician?!
!أنّ كايتو كيد كان ذاك الساحر سانادا؟
No! I watched the whole time, but he never got near the lady!
كلا، كنتُ أراقبه طوال الوقت لكنّه لم يقترب من السيّدة
Then who is it?!
من هو إذاً؟
There's one other person who could've switched cards!
يوجد شخص آخر كان بمقدوره تبديل البطاقات
Yes! That person made them fall, pretended to pick them up,
نعم، تظاهر بالمساعدة في جمع البطاقات المترامية على الأرض
then removed a card and added the message!
!وأخذ بطاقةً وألصق الرسالة عليها
They hid it in their palm and pretended to pull it from the deck!
أخفاها في راحة يده، وتظاهر بسحبه لبطاقة من المجموعة
Right, Ran-neechan?
أليس كذلك يا ران-نيتشان؟
Or should I say, Kaitou Kid-san!
بل يا كايتو كيد-سان؟
This is Chopper #1! He hasn't fled outside!
!هنا المروحيّة رقم 1! لم يحاول أحد الهروب من السفينة
This is Chopper #2! No suspicious people on deck!
هنا المروحيّة رقم 2! لا أشخاص مشبوهين !على سطح السفينة
This is Surveillance! Sonar and radar show nothing!
!هنا قسم المراقبة! لا يُظهر السونار والرادار شيئاً
Alright! Keep your eyes peeled!
!حسنٌ، أكملوا المراقبة
All onboard officers are to split up onto each floor
على كلّ الضبّاط على متن السفينة الانتشار في الطوابق
and capture the Kid on sight!
!والقبض على كيد حال رؤيته
Don't let a familiar face fool you! He's a master of disguise!
!لا ترخوا حذركم لرؤية أشخاص مألوفين !فهو متخصّص في التنكّر
Yes. You switched places with Ran when she left to find me.
أجل، أخذتَ مكان ران بعدما غادرت القاعة للبحث عنّي
Impressive. I hadn't noticed at all.
مُبهر، لم أنتبه البتّة
After becoming Ran, you agitated everyone with your message
بعدما تنكّرت بهيئتها، أثرت الهلع بين الضيوف برسالتك
and scattered the exploding pearls to cause mass panic.
ونشرتَ اللآلئ المتفجّرة لإحداث الفزع
Huh?! Your pearl is gone, too!
!ماذا؟ اختفت لؤلؤتك أيضاً يا أمّي
The Kid! He stole the Black Star!
!كان كيد! سرق كيد النجم الأسود
The fact that you prepared those fireworks means you knew
تحضيرك لتلك الألعاب النارية يعني أنّك كنت تعرف
I didn't know which one was real, and I didn't have any hints!
!لم أعرف أيّ واحدة هي الحقيقية !ولم يكن لدي أيّ تلميح حتّى
But add her dull pearl to the equation and speculation becomes certainty!
،إذا أضفتَ لمعان لؤلؤتها الخافت في الاعتبار سيتحوّل الظنّ ليقين
So it would have been obvious
لذا كان الأمر جليّاً
I was so concerned with you that I completely forgot!
أشغلتَ انتباهي فنسيتُ هذه الحقيقة تماماً
That's why you didn't take it. You knew it was a fake.
لذا لم تأخذه، عرفتَ أنّه مزيّف
Then you challenged her in your second letter
ثمّ تحدّيت السيّدة برسالتك الثانية
but you quickly dressed up as an officer during the flash,
ثمّ تنكّرت بهيئة شرطيّ سريعاً في وميض القنبلة
Besides, it's senseless to ask for help here...
كما ليس من اللائق استدعاء أحد هنا
Yes. Most great artists become famous after they die.
نعم، يشتهر مُعظم الفنّانين البارعين بعد موتهم
I'll make you a great master, Kaitou Kid.
سأجعلك أستاذاً عظيماً يا كايتو كيد
Once I place you in the cemetery known as jail.
بإرسالك للمقبرة المعروفة بالسجن
I surrender. I'll give up on this pearl.
أستسلم، سأترك لك هذه اللؤلؤة
Tell the lady I'm sorry for ruining the party!
انقل اعتذاري للسيّدة !على إفسادي حفلتها
Now you're sorry...
ماذا تقول الآن؟
Oh, yeah! The girl I knocked out to get these clothes...
بالمناسبة، الفتاة التي أفقدتها وعيها ...لأخذ هذه الملابس
She'll catch cold if we don't hurry!
!عليك الإسراع وإلّا سيصيبها الزكام
I'm a perfectionist, you see!
!فأنا أقوم بعملي على أكمل وجه
Another flash grenade!
!قنبلة ضوئية أخرى
Oh no!
!تبّاً
Damn! I won't let you escape!
!سحقاً! لن أتركك تهرب
Bastard!
!الوغد
I'll get you for this!
!سأنال منك لهذا
Hey! There's a girl asleep in this boat!
!توجد فتاة نائمة في القارب هنا
What?!
!ماذا؟
What's she doing in here? Anyway, let's get her out...
لمَ هي هنا؟ بأيّ حال، لنضعها على الأرض
Stop!
!انتظر
No! Don't take her out! Stop!
!كلا! لا تخرجها! انتظر
Huh? Wha...
ماذا؟
"This crimson dress you gave me the other day suits you wonderfully.
الفستان القرمزيّ الذي أعطيتِني إيّاه" ذاك اليوم يلائمك كثيراً
- The Occasional Dry Cleaner, Kaitou Kid"
"من عامل مغسلة الملابس في أحيان، كايتو كيد-
Bastard...
...الوغد
They later found the hang glider Kaitou Kid planned to escape with,
وجدوا لاحقاً الطائرة الشراعية التي نوى كايتو كيد الهرب عبرها غالباً
but he, himself, had completely vanished from the ship.
لكنّه اختفى تماماً من السفينة بلا أثر
Grade-schooler Protects Black Star! Kaitou Kid Thwarted!!
!طالب مميّز في الابتدائية حمى النجم الأسود بمفرده !!اعترض كايتو كيد
There you are! "Grade-schooler Protects Black Star!"
ها أنت! "طالب مميّز في الابتدائية حمى "!النجم الأسود بمفرده
You're a big hero, Conan-kun!
!أنت بطلٌ كبير يا كونان-كن
Come on, it was just luck!
كانت محض مصادفة
But you guys actually met the Kid! You're so lucky!
لكن يا لحسن حظّكما، رأيتما كيد مباشرةً
Not.
لا حسن في ذلك
Say, what did he look like?!
أخبريني، كيف كانت ملامحه؟
Ran?
ران؟
What?
ماذا؟
The Kid's face!
!أسألك عن ملامح كيد
Sorry! He knocked me out too fast...
...آسفة، أفقدني وعيي بغتةً
I saw his face, though.
رأيتُ وجهه قليلاً
What kind of older man was he?!
!أيّ رجلٍ كان؟
He was surprisingly young. In his twenties, or maybe...
،كان يافعاً لحدٍّ مُفاجئ، في عشرينياته ...أو ربما
Don't give me your cold!
!لا تنقل زكامك لي
Falling into the ocean while touring the Selizabeth! Talk about stupid!
يا إلهي، تسقط في البحر بعدما !تجوّلت على متن سيليزابيث! يا للحماقة
You're so annoying.
!اصمتي
It's that brat's fault! Swimming away was my only option!
!إنّها غلطة ذاك الصبيّ، كان الهرب سباحةً خياري الوحيد
Hey! That high-schooler...
...لحظة، ألا يشبه طالب الثانويّة ذاك
Doesn't he look like Shinichi-kun?
شينتشي-كن نوعاً ما؟
You think?
تظنّين ذلك؟
Maybe the guy you saw in Shibuya was...
قد يكون الشخص الذي ...رأيتِه في شيبويا يا ران
Whew!
!حمداً لله
That's good to hear!
!هكذا إذاً
Are you all right?!
!أأنت بخير؟
Mitsuaki-san! What's going on?!
ميتسواكي-سان! ما الذي يجري؟ !ميتسواكي-سان
But where's Mitsuaki-san?!
!أين ميتسواكي-سان؟
He's there. Down below.
إنّه موجود، أسفلنا
The Case of the Eminent Family's Strange Deaths, Part 1
قضيّة سلسلة حوادث الموت الغريبة للعائلة المرموقة (الجزء الأوّل)
On the next Conan:
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
The Case of the Eminent Family's Strange Deaths, Part 1.
قضيّة سلسلة حوادث الموت الغريبة للعائلة المرموقة ا(لجزء الأوّل)
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Detective of the West.
متحرّي الغرب
Next episode airs on October 20th.
ستبثّ الحلقة القادمة 8/5
Fu-kun, Ryo-kun, and Hazuki-chan, wait for me.
!ريوكو هازوكي-تشان الجميلة، انتظريني